Qualifications Summary

Highly skilled professional having strong business perspective to technology, with educational qualifications including M.TECHin Construction Technology and Management as well as B.Tech (Civil Engg.). Experienced in implementing handson assignments/projects involved in large multistoried Residential Complexes. Highly skilled in managing teams with a strong ability to work hard under challenging circumstances and handle multiple projects simultaneously. Construction Project Management is the overall planning, co-ordination and control of a project from inception to completion aimed at meeting a client's requirements in order to produce a functionally and financially viable project that will be completed on time within authorized cost and to the required quality standards. Project management is the process by which a project is brought to a successful conclusion. Construction project management (CPM) is project management that applies to the construction sector.

Professional Experience (`13+ YEARS)

My Weblink :- https://www.linkedin.com/in/avtar-singh-62697418

Present :-

2015 – 2018 To date Present working with M/s **International Land Developer www.ild.co.in**

Position: AGM / Sr. Project Manager (Projects)

Project: The ARETE, Sector 33 & GSR Drive Sec 36 Sohna Gurgaon, ild Grand / Greens Sector 37C Gurgaon

Responsibilities: To Achieve Construction Milestones, Progress review meetings with Contractors / Architect / Consultants, Monitoring & Co-ordination, MIS

Past :-

2011 – 2015 was working with BPTP Limited

Position: Project Manager (Projects)

Project: The Resort Residential Building Greater Faridabad

Responsibilities: Handing Over Incharge, Progress review, Monitoring & Co-

ordination

Past :-

2006 – 2011 WithUNITECH LIMITED

Position: Project Manager (Co-ordination & Monitoring)

Projects: 1. Projects in Noida & Greater Noida of M/s UNITECH

LIMITED

Responsibilities:

- Handing Over Incharge
- Progress review
- Monitoring progress & Analyzing variance



Nationality: **Indian**

À Languages

English, Hindi, Punjabi



Present Address:

Status Residency Trehan, Flat no. 1108, Floor no. 11 Tower- A1 Tapukara, Bhiwadi Alwar bypass highway.

Mobile:

09891052364 (Direct no.)

Permanent Address:

House No. 266 Mohalla Khanda Kholla Achli Gate Batala, Dist. Gurdaspur.. State Punjab - 143505

E-mail:

singh78659@gmail.com

- Site Execution & Monitoring construction inc. providing inputs on methodology.
- Pre- arrangement of material required to finish the project on time.
- Coordinating with the contractor / architect for detailed construction document.
- Implementing QA/QC procedure and ensure quality assurance.
- Overseeing contractor bill verification and follow ups for payments.
- Checking of quality/quantity of the material to be used.
- Management of staff
- Taking the reviews from staff weekly to monitor the project.
- Scheduling the site, by preparing duty charts as per staff, for timely execution of the project.
- Detail study of the Inventory Control System & prepare charts of analysis.
- Detail study of the Activity Based Costing & conduct the flow charts showing the detail progress of actual Vs planned work.
- Prepare the progress monitoring charts to track the productivity.
- Developing effective communications and mechanisms for resolving conflicts.

ADDITIONAL RESPONSIBILITIES with M/s UNITECH LIMITED

Position: CORE TEAM MEMBER (CTM)

Projects: SAP ECC 6.0

Responsibilities: Work & Complete the Project System (PS) Module

Material Management (MM) Module Quality Management (QM) Module

Document Management System (DMS) Module

Achievements: Completed & submitted the Current State Business Process (CSBP)

Future State Business Process (FSBP)

Business Blue Print (BBP)

ADDITIONAL RESPONSIBILITIES with M/s International Land Developer

Project: Monitoring&Control the Construction Activities of ild Green / ild Grand & Engratia Projects, To achieve the Construction Milestones within stipulated time frame.

PRESENT REPORTING TO:- DIRECT REPORTING TO MANAGEMENT REPRESENTATIVE VICE - PRESIDENT OF M/s International Land Developer

Current Salary Package :- 25 Lacs Per Year Expected Salary CTC :- 30 Lacs Per Year

Exposure to Information Technology

Project Management Tools MS Project CAD Tools AutoCAD R 14

Word-Processing tools MS - Word, MS - PowerPoint, MS-Excel

Educational Qualifications (Regular)

❖ M.TECH in Construction Technology & Management from Giani Zail Singh Collage of Engineering and Technology.

Topic of the Thesis: Steel Fiber Reinforced Concrete (SFRC)

- ❖ B.TECH (Civil Engg.) from Giani Zail Singh Collage of Engineering and Technology, Bathinda (PTU). http://www.gzscampus.org/https://www.ptu.ac.in
 - Final Year project, "Analysis & Design of 6 storied residential building".
 - > Industrial Training from Anuradha Apartment projects, New Delhi.

Skills & Strength

- Honesty and Integrity.
- Hard Working & Determined.
- Good Analytical skills.
- Good Communication skills.
- Don't get discouraged by trivial setbacks.
- Fast & Flexible Team Player
- Good Leadership Skills.
- Positive Attitude.

AVTAR SINGH